#### BERHANE TEKLEMARIAM

## Summary

Seasoned UI/UX designer with 4+ years experience in building, maintaining and designing responsive websites.

I am proficient in React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and jQuery. I love learning new domains, and easily adapt to new environments, technologies and workflows.

## **Skills**

### Languages

JavaScript, ReactJS, CSS3, HTML5, Typescript, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

#### **Databases**

MYSQL, MongoDB

#### **Frameworks**

Redux jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap, WordPress, bulma, Adobe Photoshop & illustrator

#### **Tools**

Git/github, Heroku, Firebase, Node etc.

## Work Experience

## Front-End DevelopeR - Zemen, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia - April 2017 - june 2018

- Developed both front-end and back-end features for apps using standard REST APIs, TDD/BDD, Intellij, JQuery, Spark in React, Java
  and IS
- developing responsive web applications across platforms using React in front end ,javaScript, Ajax,Axios,and Adobe photoshop
- analyzed UI/UX design for responsive layout for improved usability.
- creating Api endpoints to connect calls made from the front end to the databases and vice versa.
- Developed both front-end and back-end features for apps using standard REST APIs, TDD/BDD, Intellij, JQuery, Spark in React, Java and JS.

## JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER (FULL TIME) - Dana IT, Eritrea - April 2016—Feb 2017

- Developed both front-end and back-end features for apps using standard REST APIs, TDD/BDD, Intellij, JQuery, Spark in React, Java and JS.
- Designed and built a web page which helps users to get filtered news according to their mood(positive,neutral and negative) using Vader sentiment ,HTML,CSS,JavaScript and React
- Developed applications, user interface, and RESTful API to be consumed by various modules.
- Work as part of a team as well as work autonomously.
- Rewrite existing code, and add new code on top of pre-existing code

# Web Developer (Full time) - Absari enterprise, , Eritrea - Jan 2014 – Feb 2016

- Designed, developed and tested HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery and React.JS that meets accessibility and web browser standards for websites.
- Worked on responsive design and developed a single ISOMORPHIC responsive website that could be served to desktop, Tablets and mobile users using React.js.
- Improved & created new features on the project using react.js
- Designed and maintained an Eritrean website www.kebhi.com which Integrated all the frontend and backend components and used cloud storage for the backend.

## Education

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP - UC Berkeley extension, California-2020 BSC in Computer science - Eritrean Institute of Technology, Eritrea- 2008-2013